CHERYL RENEE GIVENS

1516 Harwell Drive Apt 1622, Arlington, TX H: 972-854-4921 | givens_cr@yahoo.com

Summary

1 year assisting clients whom are suffering from addiction and substance use in a treatment facility. 11 years of data and information technology and financial banking experience. 20 years of Proactive, friendly customer service, professional attitude, and demeanor. Strong organizational, multitasking, and communication skills. Effective ability to work and interact in a team environment.

- Communication Skills
- Listening and Teaching Classes Cognitive, Budgeting, Anger Management
- Therapy and treatment plan
- Team development

- Research and analysis
- Microsoft proficiency
- Conflict management
- Customer service-oriented

Experience

Student 03/2018 to 12/2018

Salvation Army Substance Abuse Center

- Teach and assist with clients whom are in the substance program who are transitioning from prison; Dallas County, Texas Correctional; Teaching group therapy for men and women.
- Teaching Life skills, coping skills, Job Readiness and initiating a program that assist clients with writing/computer skills, educational and job readiness.
- Also recording initial treatment plan and filing of documents.

02/2018 to 03/2018

Nexus Treatment Center for Women Dallas, PRN

- Assist adolescence girls ages 13-17 with daily routines, Maintain accurate documentation.
- Monitor clients' treatment progress and assist in treatment adherence.

09/2017 to 04/2018 **Contact Specialist** Dallas, TX

Aafes/ Department of Defense

- Responds to veterans, active ad retired about account information or inquiries.
- Research and provide immediate response to related credit program accounts/Military Star.
- Trouble shoot customers account, provide technical assistance threw DEERS and vet verify to assist military personnel with log on/username issues.

Education and Training

Master's Degree: Professional Counseling

2018

Grand Canyon University

Bachelors of Science: Computer Information Systems, Marketing

2006

Grambling State University

Grambling, LA

Activities and Honors

Member of American Counseling Association